Guide to the Yasser Alwan Collection 1890-1970 AD.MC.002
AbuDhabi
- Series II: Egypt, 1895-1971 (Box 1-7)
  - A family group pose at the top of some stairs in front of a bulding.13.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Architecture; Buildings; Doors; Egypt; Family Portraits; French Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Suits; Women
  - A young woman in a patterned dress, looking off camera. 13.3 x 8.4 cm, 3 October 1930; Studio M. Georgiladakis, Suez, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 19)
    French Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Jewellery; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suez, Egypt; Women
  - A woman in a polka dot dress with a large bow. 13.5 x 8.5 cm, 20 February 1930; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Egypt; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Italian Writing; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
  - Three young males, reading a Kodak guide. 13.8 x 8.6 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Boys; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Reading; Studio Photography; Suits
  - A bride and groom on a stepped platform. 14.0 x 8.6 cm, 11 December 1937; Venus Photo Studio, Ex Studio Hanselmann, A. Artinian, Le Caire, 44 Rue Kasr El Nil (Egypt) (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Brides; Cairo, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Grooms; Italian Writing; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Wedding Dresses; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veils; Women
  - A woman wearing a wide-brimmed hat, holding a parasol. 13.4 x 8.5 cm, 5 August 1931; Studio Kerop, Cairo, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Cairo, Egypt; Fashion Accessories; French Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
  - Two boys dressed as French Foreign Legion soldiers. 13.7 x 8.5 cm, 10 June 1922; Sociedad Artistico Fotografia, Cáceres (Spain) (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Boys; Costumes; Cáceres, Spain; Flags; French Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Guns; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Uniforms
  - A young woman wearing a striped dress and beaded necklace. 13.9 x 8.5 cm, Undated; Studio N. Kolokotronis, Port Said, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Jewellery; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Port Said, Egypt; Shoes; Studio Photography; Women
  - A young man in a suit, with his hands behind his back. 13.5 x 8.5 cm, 30 July 1924; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Bow Ties; Egypt; French Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Handkerchief; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
  - A portrait of a young man in soft focus. 13.9 x 9.0 cm, 1927; Venus Photo Studio, Ex Studio Hanselmann, A. Artinian, Le Caire, 44 Rue Kasr El Nil (Egypt) (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Cairo, Egypt; English Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Signature; Studio Photography; Suits
  - A young woman holding a bouquet of flowers. 13.7 x 8.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Egypt; Flowers; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Individual Portraits; Jewellery; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
  - A young girl wearing a dress with geometric patterns. 13.7 x 8.6 cm, 10 April 1936; Studio Kerop, Cairo, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Cairo, Egypt; Children; French Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - A wedding portrait, the groom holds a pair of white gloves. 13.9 x 8.7 cm, 5 December 1947; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Bow Ties; Brides; Egypt; Flowers; Gelatin Silver Prints; Gloves; Grooms; Men; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Wedding Dresses; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veils; Women
  - An Effendi, wearing a tarbouche. 13.5 x 8.6 cm, 20 November 1921; Art Photo Studio, R. A. Galea, 14 Av. Choubrah, Caire (Egypt) (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Arabic Writing; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
  - A bearded man in a utility jacket with two large breast pockets. 13.5 x 8.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Arabic Writing; Beards; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - A group on the beach in Sidi Beshir. A 8.8 x 13.7 cm, 1946; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Arabic Writing; Bathing Suits / Swimsuits; Beaches; Children; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Women
  - An elderly man wearing a tarbouche, smoking a cigarette. Text on reverse: M. Bounol, Beaux-Arts. 13.8 x 8.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Cigarettes; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Smoking
  - A hand-painted image of a woman wearing a blouse with polka dots. 13.6 x 8.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hand-colored Photographs / Hand-tinting; Individual Portraits; Makeup; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
  - A boy dressed in a uniform, with a hat reading "Nazionale Balilla", an Italian Fascist youth organization. 13.5 x 8.7 cm, 9 November 1931; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Boys; Fascists; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Italian Writing; Italy; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Uniforms; Unknown Locations
  - A young girl in a short furry coat. 13.4 x 8.3 cm, April 1927; Lux el Umbra, Viale XX Settembre 24, Trieste (Italy) (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Coats; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Hats; Individual Portraits; Italian Writing; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Trieste, Italy
  - A mother and daughter, the girl is wearing a dress and veil, holding a small book (bible ?). Linked ref465. 13.3 x 8.4 cm, Undated; Studio M. Georgiladakis, Suez, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Books; Event study; Family Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Head Covers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suez, Egypt; Women
  - A girl in a white dress with a veil. Linked ref464. 13.4 x 8.4 cm, Undated; Studio M. Georgiladakis, Suez, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Books; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suez, Egypt
  - A girl in a white dress and a white beret. 13.4 x 8.5 cm, 24 December 1927; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Egypt; French Writing; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Hats; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - Three women and a man sitting on some steps, the man is balancing a hat on his foot. Same four people from ref469. 8.7 x 13.9 cm, Circa 1928; G. Gabler, Wien I, Volksgarten, briefadress: Wien XIV, Felberstr 60 (Vienna, Austria); Gabler, G. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Archaeological Sites; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Hats; Men; Photographic Prints; Vienna, Austria; Women
  - The Maria Theresa Denkmal Square in Vienna, Austria. Same four adults as ref468. 13.9 x 8.9 cm, 1928; Photograph Weiss, Wien X, Karmarschg 73 (Vienna, Austria) (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Architecture; French Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Monuments; Photographic Prints; Statues; Vienna, Austria; Women
  - A young boy in a sailor outfit. 13.9 x 9.1 cm, 10 June 1922; Torron, Jose (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Boys; Children; French Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Maritime Outfits; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Uniforms; Ávila, Spain
  - A hand-painted portrait of a young girl sitting on a chair in a garden. 13.2 x 8.6 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Egypt; Furnishings; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Hand-colored Photographs / Hand-tinting; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints
  - A young man wearing a suit, with shorts. 13.8 x 8.7 cm, Undated; Studio Hana (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Boys; Clocks & Watches; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
  - A woman with makeup and jewellery looking off camera. 13.8 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - A man wearing a suit. Arabic text on reverse: "From Hassan Al Sayyid Al Hashem to Ahmed Beg Vahiddin." 13.8 x 8.7 cm, Undated; Studio Vart, Cairo, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Arabic Writing; Cairo, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Jewellery; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
  - Two men sitting at a cafe, one smoking shisha. 14.0 x 8.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Nargiles; Photographic Prints; Restaurants; Shisha; Smoking; Suits
  - Two men sitting in a garden. Arabic text on reverse "My weight is 63 kg.". 9.0 x 13.9 cm, 19 August 1923; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Arabic Writing; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Suits
  - Three women with a baby. Photo London, Cairo, Egypt. 8.4 x 13.5 cm, Undated; Studio Photo London, 13 Rue Emad El Dine, Cairo (Egypt) (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Babies; Cairo, Egypt; Family; Family Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
  - Kamal Bey, Chief Engineer of Irrigation. 14.0 x 8.9 cm, 2 September 1949; Studio P. Pierotti, Roma, Botteghe Oscure (Italy) (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Buildings; Egypt; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Minia, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Postal Stamps; Postcards; Studio Photography
  - A group of Boy Scout masters. 8.8 x 11.6 cm, 1946; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Boy Scouts; Boys; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Head Covers; Men; Photographic Prints
  - Two men with round glasses, wearing hats. 13.9 x 8.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Clocks & Watches; Egypt; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
  - Two men feeding pigeons in the Piazza St. Marco in Venice. 13.9 x 9.0 cm, Undated; Studio Fotografi Autorizzati S. Marco, Sede Sociale: Pnte Canonica 4320, Venezia (Italy) (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Architecture; Birds; Books; Buildings; Coats; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Venice, Italy
  - A child with a bike. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Bicycles; Children; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints
  - A crowd of men at the entrance of a building, some men in suits are gathered around a table. 9.0 x 13.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Audiences; Crowds; Egypt; Events / Occasions; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Officials; Photographic Prints; Suits; Turban
  - Three men looking at an engraving of birds. 8.9 x 13.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Birds; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints
  - Two women sitting at a table. 9.0 x 13.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewellery; Photographic Prints; Women
  - Men in suits posing with men in traditional dress. 8.8 x 13.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Crowds; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Hats; Men; Photographic Prints; Suits; Traditional Dress
  - Three men wearing suits and a Coptic priest. 8.9 x 13.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Coptic Dress; Egypt; Events / Occasions; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Officials; Photographic Prints; Priests; Religious Clothing
  - Officials in a court room. 8.9 x 13.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Cameras; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Officials; Photographic Prints; Suits
  - A woman in a dark satin dress, holding a purse. 13.6 x 8.7 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Bags; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Jewellery; Makeup; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
  - A family riding on a carnival ride. 9.0 x 13.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Men shaking hands over a table (linked ref494). 9.0 x 14.2 cm, August 1962; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Arabic Writing; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Officials; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
  - Boys in bathing suits posing in front of building. 8.8 x 13.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Bathing Suits / Swimsuits; Beaches; Buildings; Children; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Swimming; Women
  - Two men with sunglasses, surrounded by boys. 8.6 x 11.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Audiences; Boys; Crowds; Egypt; Events / Occasions; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Suits
  - Four men sitting around a desk (linked ref491). 9.0 x 14.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Arabic Writing; Egypt; Events / Occasions; Fezes / Tarbouches; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Officials; Photographic Prints; Suits
  - An Effendi standing in front of a wooden door, holding a document. 13.8 x 8.7 cm, 8 August 1925; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Arabic Writing; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Signature; Suits
  - A street view of a building. 9.0 x 14.0 cm, 1928; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Buildings; Children; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Men; Photographic Prints; Signs / Signposts; Streets
  - A group pose in a garden. 14.0 x 9.0 cm, Undated; Sargologo, Georges (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Constantinople; Family Portraits; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Head Covers; Istanbul, Turkey; Jewellery; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Women
  - Three young females on a balcony. 9.4 x 13.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Balcony / Terrace; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Women
  - A belly dancer, standing in front of painted backdrop. 10.0 x 15.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Arabic Writing; Belly Dancers; Dancing; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Jewellery; Makeup; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Stage; Women
  - A MISR AIR Ad - two women lying on the ground in front of a MISR AIR plane. 11.7 x 16.6 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Advertisements; Airplanes; Arabic Writing; Cairo, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Women
  - A MISR AIR advertisment, woman holding a propeller. 11.5 x 17.7 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Advertisements; Airplanes; Arabic Writing; Cairo, Egypt; Costumes; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Women
  - A man sitting in a chair on the beach. Same man as ref503. 17.5 x 11.5 cm, 1954; Studio S. Abbas (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Arabic Writing; Bathing Suits / Swimsuits; Beaches; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints
  - A man in front of a car. Same man from ref502. 11.4 x 17.3 cm, 1957; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Arabic Writing; Cars; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Suits
  - A woman with two young girls in dresses sitting next to a fireplace. Same young girls from ref505. 17.6 x 11.1 cm, Undated; Studio Selim Youssef, Camera Artist, 44 Soliman Pasha, Cairo (Egypt) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Cairo, Egypt; Family Portraits; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Houses; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
  - Two young girls in white dresses sitting on a couch. Same girls from ref504. 17.1 x 10.6 cm, Undated; Studio Selim Youssef, Camera Artist, 44 Soliman Pasha, Cairo (Egypt) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Cairo, Egypt; Family Portraits; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Houses; Jewellery; Makeup; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - A young woman in a black bathing suit, sitting on a railing. 18.1 x 13.1 cm, 4 September 1962; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Bathing Suits / Swimsuits; Cars; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Streets; Unknown Locations; Women
  - A young woman posing behind a tree. 11.8 x 17.6 cm, 13 August 1948; Photo-Surprise, Avenue Des Français Beyrouth (Lebanon) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Beirut, Lebanon; Buildings; Countryside / Rural; French Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Trees; Women
  - A woman posing on a rock in a bathing suit. 13.0 x 18.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Bathing Suits / Swimsuits; Beaches; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Seas; Women
  - Airline crew members. Czech stamp on the back. 13.3 x 18.2 cm, Undated; Obrazové zpravodajstvi ČTK. Autorské právo vyhrazeno (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Airplanes; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Unknown Locations; Women
  - Nigar Sultana, an Indian actress. 15.0 x 10.3 cm, 1955; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Arabic Writing; Egypt; English Writing; Film actor; Gelatin Silver Prints; India; Individual Portraits; Jewellery; Makeup; Photographic Prints; Women
  - A woman wearing a hat with a tassel. There is an additional print of the same photo. 15.2 x 20.2 cm, 1924; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
  - Boys jumping off the Aswan Dam. 11.3 x 8.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Boys; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Swimming
  - A young soldier of regiment 21. 13.9 x 9.0 cm, 25 July 1926; Studio A. Scavo et Fils Photographes, Beyrouth (Lebanon) (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Beirut, Lebanon; French Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Lebanon; Men; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Signature; Studio Photography; Uniforms
  - A man standing at a microphone addressing a large crowd. 14.5 x 12.7 cm, Undated; Al Musayabi, Mohamed, Sanaa, Yemen (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Architecture; Audiences; Boys; Buildings; Crowds; Events / Occasions; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Microphones; Photographic Prints; Sanaa, Yemen
  - A young woman with long, braided hair. 13.9 x 9.4 cm, Undated; Studio Badr (Egypt) (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Arabic Writing; Egypt; Film actor; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Makeup; Photographic Prints; Women
  - A family group on a beach, a pier is in the background. Same woman from ref518. 14.4 x 9.5 cm, 1947; Studio Philippe, Cairo, Egypt (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Beaches; Boys; Egypt; Family Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Seas; Studio Photography; Women
  - A woman on the beach holding a cigarette. Same woman from ref517. 9.7 x 14.7 cm, 1945; Studio Philippe, Cairo, Egypt (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Beaches; Cigarettes; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Seas; Smoking; Studio Photography; Women
  - A girl in a checkered dress, posing in front of a boat on the Nile. Same girl from ref520. 15.7 x 10.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Boats; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Individual Portraits; Nile River; Photographic Prints
  - Two young girls standing on the bank of the Nile River. Same girl from ref519. 15.4 x 10.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Nile River; Photographic Prints
  - A young woman at the coast. 11.9 x 11.9 cm, 1951; Studio Photo Simon (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Arabic Writing; Beaches; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Jewellery; Makeup; Photographic Prints; Seas; Studio Photography; Women
  - A woman with hoop earrings. 15.1 x 9.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Arabic Writing; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Jewellery; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
  - Two women with white handbags. 14.4 x 10.0 cm, Undated; Studio Photo D'art, Const. Rittas, 2 Egilae Copt, Alexandrie 72 (Egypt) (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Alexandria, Egypt; Fashion Accessories; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
  - A woman wearing a long, formal gown. 17.2 x 11.1 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Egypt; Evening gown / Ball gown; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Jewellery; Makeup; Photographic Prints; Signature; Studio Photography; Women
  - A woman wearing a polka dot dress, looking off camera. 16.5 x 12.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Arabic Writing; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Jewellery; Makeup; Photographic Prints; Women
  - An Effendi. 14.9 x 10.6 cm, 12 October 1939; Studio Armand, Midan Suares, Cairo (Egypt) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Cairo, Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
  - A bride and groom. 17.0 x 11.7 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Brides; Egypt; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Fezes / Tarbouches; Flowers; Gelatin Silver Prints; Grooms; Makeup; Men; Photographic Prints; Wedding Dresses; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veils; Women
  - Two saints with halos over their heads. Arabic writing on the front. 17.1 x 11.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Arabic Writing; Cyrillic Writing; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Saints
  - Two saints with halos. Arabic and Cyrillic writing on the front. 17.0 x 10.6 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - A woman, wearing a large beaded necklace. 9.1 x 6.1 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - A close-up portrait of a young woman. 17.4 x 11.4 cm, Undated; Garo, Studio d'Art, 40 Rue Kasr El Nil, Le Caire (Egypt) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - A young man wearing a short tie. 10.7 x 6.7 cm, Undated; Bayazhniyan, B. M., Shumen, Bulgaria (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Bulgaria; Cyrillic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
  - A man with a handlebar mustache. 10.5 x 6.6 cm, Undated; Studio Phebus, Grand Rue de Pera No. 301, au-deasus de la Maison Flament, Constantinople (Istanbul) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Arabic Writing; Constantinople; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Suits
  - A woman wearing a coat with a fur collar, holding a plant. 12.2 x 6.9 cm, 2 March 1931; Studio d'Art Lazar, Ibrahimieh (Alexandria, Egypt) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Coats; Egypt; Fur Garments; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
  - A woman wearing a satin dress and long gloves.. 18.1 x 9.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Arabic Writing; Egypt; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Gloves; Individual Portraits; Makeup; Photographic Prints; Women
  - Three women and a man on an ornate wooden couch. 13.3 x 18.1 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Arabic Writing; Drinking; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Unknown Locations; Women
  - A group of men in a crowded room, one man stands above the rest. 12.0 x 18.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Arabic Writing; Audiences; Cigarettes; Crowds; Egypt; Events / Occasions; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Smoking; Suits
  - A group of men in suits and tarbouches on a train car on a bridge. 12.5 x 17.3 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Bridges; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Nile River; Photographic Prints; Suits; Trains
  - A mosque with some wagons amd horses out front. Same mosque as ref542. 12.9 x 18.1 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Architecture; Carriages & Coaches; Cars; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Horses; Mosques; Photographic Prints